Be the owner wherever you are
I'm a high school student
attending boarding school.
My family has had a bad history
with alcohol abuse.
(Sunim) I see.
My father used to drink a lot
in the past, although he now doesn't.
Both of my grandfathers passed away early
due to health issues from alcoholism.
From an early age, I experienced
such deaths and thought to myself,
''What would happen once we die?'
It might sound funny but I thought
about death a lot from an early age.
And I sought answers to
my questions through religion.
I had no family or friends
that were Christian.
But I went to church by myself
since I was nine,
as means to seek an answer.
Sunday school studies taught me
that Christians will go to heaven,
non-Christians will go to hell.
I believed the pastor's every word.
The church I went to
was a conservative evangelical church.
Now that I've become
a high school student,
I've become disgusted with the teachings
that claim believers go to heaven,
non-believers go to hell.
As a Christian,
how should I love those
with other religious faiths?
(Sunim) I understand your question.
How do you define a Christian?
A Christian believes in
Jesus Christ's sacrifice
and follows his teachings.
(Sunim) A follower of Christ, right?
Jesus came to this world
2000 years ago, didn't he?
After he spent 40 days
in the wilderness,
the holy spirit came down from the sky
in the form of a dove and said to him,
"You are my beloved son."
The Bible says that God's voice
spoke those words, right?
So Jesus became aware then,
that he was not a son of a carpenter,
but the only son of God.
Knowing that he was
the only son of God,
would he have had anything
to fear for in this world?
(Questioner) No, he wouldn't have.
(Sumin) That's right.
So, he went out to the world
and started spreading the gospel.
But his gospel was different from
the teachings of traditional Judaism.
And that caused friction.
One of the points of contention
with the Jewish doctrine was this:
Judaism is based on the notion
that Jewish people are the chosen ones.
Jewish people believe that
they were chosen by God
and that only Jews can be saved by God.
Gentiles cannot be saved by God.
Only Jews can be saved.
That is the notion
of the 'chosen people'.
The criterion for salvation
is a racial and ethnic one.
In such case, would Gentiles want to
believe in Judaism or not?
(Questioner) They would not.
They would not.
Because Gentiles cannot be saved.
And yet what did Jesus say?
He said Gentiles,
those who are not Jewish,
can be saved too.
At that time, that was
an inconceivable idea
that caused a huge outcry.
"How dare you speak those
heretical things?", people said.
It makes logical sense now
but back then,
what Jesus was saying
was totally unorthodox.
It caused outrage and disorder
among society.
Jesus said to his critics:
"There was a gravely ill person
abandoned on the street.
Nobody took care of him.
The Levite and Jewish priest
walked past him without helping him.
But a Samaritan took care of him
until he got well."
With this specific story he asked,
"Who would God bless in this case?"
Critics listening responded,
"The Samaritan, of course."
This is the parable
of the Good Samaritan.
It illustrates how God saves Jews
and Gentiles alike.
While the Judaism's criterion
for salvation is based on race,
to Jesus,
those who are saved
are not of a particular race
or ethnic group.
It's regarding those who have mercy
and compassion for others,
and how they behave accordingly.
If you read Matthew 25:
When the Son of Man comes in his glory,
all the nations will be gathered
before him.
He will divide the people
as a shepherd would divide the sheep
from the goats.
On his left he will say,
"Depart from me, into the eternal fire.
For I was hungry
and you gave me nothing to eat,
I was thirsty
and you gave me nothing to drink,
I was a stranger
and you did not invite me in,
I needed clothes
and you did not clothe me,
I was sick and in prison
and you did not look after me."
They will answer ‘Lord, when did we
see you so, and did not help you?’
He will say ‘Whatever you did not do
for one of the least of these,
you didn't do for me.’
This is the criterion
of Christ's salvation.
It's clearly written in the bible.
The bible doesn't say whether
the sun revolves around the earth or not.
Jesus doesn't say.
Maybe it's in the old testament.
So how would you
apply his teachings?
Let's say here's an injured person,
and a priest and a preacher
just passed by him.
And yet a Buddhist monk saw him
and took care of him.
Who would please God the most?
The same principles apply.
If we go back to
the most fundamental principles
of Christ's teachings,
to say that salvation can only be found
within church
and the catholic system is to revert
back to traditional Judaic logic.
It means Christianity
is reverting back to old Judaic doctrine.
It's as if Buddhists say
that a stupid one will
reincarnate as a cow,
a greedy one will be a pig,
and such-and-such will become a dog, etc.
This is Hinduism, not Buddhism principle.
But don't Buddhists these days
mistakenly take it as Buddhism?
It's important for you
to go back to Christ's teachings
at its purest form.
How remarkable
was Christ's love?
When he was condemned
for bringing disorder to society
and nailed to the cross,
he said, "Father, forgive them,
for they do not know what they're doing."
We cannot even come close
to imitating such a love.
Even if people could abuse
and kill his body,
his spirit and soul
could not be damaged.
That is the principle
of resurrection.
The body can die,
but the spirit lives on.
In my opinion, the lesson
of the story is not
whether his body resurrected
after three days or not.
So don't try to find your answers
in other faiths.
You can find
the all-embracing compassion
in your own Christian faith.
So go back to Christ's core teaching.
If you have further questions, ask.
That was very helpful.
I was conflicted between coming here
and going to church service today.
(Audience) Laughter
(Audience) Applause
(Questioner) I feel that God has
reached me to open up through you.
(Questioner) I pray that you and
Jesus will always be with me.
(Sunim) Ok.
There is no contradiction in me
talking based on Christian principles.
Why is that?
Per Christian logic,
everything in this world
is a creation of God.
That makes me a creation of God too.
The creator shows himself
through his creation.
He shows his beliefs
Hence it makes sense for the creator
to show his will through me.
Hence you can receive God's grace
through me too.
In my opinion,
there are a lot of commonalities
between Buddhist practice
and the biblical teachings.
The Buddhist practice teaches
that in whatever situation,
you should always be
in charge of your situation.
We say, "Be the master of yourself
wherever you are."
Similarly, the Bible says,
"Whoever compels you to go one mile,
go with him two"
"If someone demands your coat,
offer your shirt also."
That means this:
Let's say someone demands
that you go a mile
and you drag yourself along.
Then you are under his control,
are you not?
And yet if you tell him,
"I'll go two miles instead.",
who is owning the situation?
You are now in charge of the situation.
Even when Jesus was nailed
to the cross and his body was damaged,
Jesus's mind and spirit was invincible.
When we are sick, our mind and spirit
become enslaved to our bodily suffering.
But for Jesus, his spirit
was independent from his body.
He asked for forgiveness
for his perpetrators.
What do we call that
in Buddhist terms?
That is Enlightenment.
That is Nirvana.
That is the state where the body
can perish but the spirit is invincible.
Let's say you are not
even a Buddhist.
Let's say you are Christian
and your husband cheated on you.
You could think, "How dare he!"
But if you reflect on how Jesus
forgave those who killed him,
is your husband's indiscretion
such an unforgivable act?
If you think from a place of faith,
is it all that unforgivable?
If you cannot forgive, then
you're not acting according to your faith.
While it's easier to be
unforgiving in reality,
you can adopt a different way
of perceiving problems
as a true Christian.
If you can live
according to your religious beliefs,
this can influence others
to admire and follow.
The distinction
between religions or sects
within a religion are not important.
I'm not saying
they are all the same.
They all hold a different way
of seeing the world.
But we need to transcend
those differences
and perceive the truth.
Buddha taught us
how to overcome differences
and perceive the truth as-is.
He did not teach us to draw lines
and exclude under the name of religion.
We've created a fence
under the name of Buddhism.
We've created different sects
and have drawn distinctions among them.
Instead of seeking the truth,
we've created false images of the truth.
Those images are not
the truth themselves.
Laozi also said,
"The Tao that can be spoken
is not the eternal Tao"
We need to look beyond ourselves
and seek the path beyond.
Only then can we reach Enlightenment.
Today a young woman mentioned
she had been sexually harassed
by her father.
Ethically speaking, this woman
cannot be free from this incident.
But in the framework of essential truth,
she is pristine.
As long as she lets go of her foolish
thoughts and
understand that no one
can ultimately harm her,
she is instantly free.
The question is
whether she selects the path
to enlightenment and freedom,
or she holds onto foolish thoughts
and selects the path to suffering.
It's ultimately her own choice
whether she becomes a Buddha
or stay a layman.
And yet most of you here choose
to stay a layman.
Hence you continue to suffer.
You can always choose
the path of Buddha instead.
And yet you've become accustomed
to living your way.
Even if you claim
you'll be taking the path of Buddha,
you inevitably find yourself
on the other path.
It is because you've grown a habit.
It's as if you've claimed
to stop smoking,
and yet you find yourself smoking
once a friend starts smoking.
You can always acknowledge
your habit and head back.
You will makes mistakes a few times
but you can always come back.
Anyone can. Anyone can.
Every living being can
become a Buddha.
The way to Enlightenment is
open to anyone
in any situation.